<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<books created="2006-08-20">
    <introduction>A list of books I read.</introduction>
    <!-- TODO: replace links to Google Books with links to Goodreads -->
    <book>
        <date></date>
        <title>The Tripods: All For Nothing?</title>
        <subtitle>The Secrets and Stories Behind the BBC Series</subtitle>
        <author>Chris Jones</author>
        <publishingyear>2024</publishingyear>
        <rating></rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/219082861</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments></comments>
        <image>The Tripods - All For Nothing.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2025-12-06</date>
        <title>La Place</title>
        <author>Annie Ernaux</author>
        <publishingyear>1983</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Place</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Je découvre Annie Ernaux un peu par hasard. Je cherchais une lecture courte. <i>La Place</i> est un livre court, certes, mais aussi très prenant. J'aime beaucoup le style de l'auteur et également le thème biographique, l'histoire de ce père appartenant à un autre temps et ayant une personnalité toute autre que celle de sa fille.</comments>
        <image>La Place.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2025-11-23</date>
        <title>La Chatte</title>
        <author>Colette</author>
        <publishingyear>1933</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Chatte_(roman)</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Uns lecture beaucoup plus facile que <i>Moderato cantabile</i>, qui m'a fait du bien. Cette rivalité femme/chatte est un peu surréaliste, mais fonctionne bien.</comments>
        <image>La Chatte.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2025-10-22</date>
        <title>Moderato cantabile</title>
        <author>Marguerite Duras</author>
        <publishingyear>1958</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moderato_cantabile</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Je ne suis apparemment pas fan de Marguerite Duras. Cela faisait longtemps que je ne m'étais pas ennuyé ainsi en lisant un livre. Je peux en reconnaître les qualités objectives, mais, dans la pratique, je n'ai eu aucun plaisir à le lire.</comments>
        <image>Moderato cantabile.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2025-08-29</date>
        <title>Moral Ambition</title>
        <subtitle>Stop Wasting Your Talent and Start Making a Difference</subtitle>
        <author>Rutger Bregman</author>
        <publishingyear>2025</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.75</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/218372426</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>I read this book after hearing a conversation between Bregman and Sam Harris. I thought it might bring back some of my interest in effective altruism. In the end, the book is mostly a series of stories about people who did very ethical and impactful things in their lives. It doesn't really offer a clear method. How can we reconcile our modern lives - family, children, work - with more impactful actions? I still don't know. I guess one conclusion could be: don't let perfect be the enemy of good.</comments>
        <image>Moral Ambition.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2025-05-09</date>
        <title>Le Désert des Tartares</title>
        <author>Dino Buzzati</author>
        <publishingyear>1940</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_D%C3%A9sert_des_Tartares</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Un excellent roman, à propos du temps qui passe, de l'attente, de la guerre (et de son absurdité) et, finalement, du sens de la vie. On pourrait même dire que c'est aussi un livre à propos de la crise de la quarantaine, un concept qui, j'imagine, n'est apparu que bien plus tard.</comments>
        <image>Le Désert des Tartares.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2025-03-18</date>
        <title>The Singularity Is Nearer</title>
        <subtitle>When We Merge with AI</subtitle>
        <author>Ray Kurzweil</author>
        <publishingyear>2024</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Singularity_Is_Nearer</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Shorter than <i>The Singularity Is Near</i>. I'm not sure I learned anything new. I'm quite convinced that AI is on the path described by Kurzweil for a couple of decades now. Kurzweil predicts that AI will reach human intelligence by 2029. I'm still not sure about nanotechnology and nanobots, though. Kurzweil predicts that, in the 2030s, nanobots could enter our bodies, repair our cells, etc. This sounds exciting, but harder to believe, somehow.</comments>
        <image>The Singularity Is Nearer.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2025-01-20</date>
        <title>Au bonheur des ogres</title>
        <author>Daniel Pennac</author>
        <publishingyear>1985</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Au_bonheur_des_ogres</url>
        <image>Au bonheur des ogres.jpg</image>
        <comments>La deuxième (peut-être même troisième) fois que je lis ce livre de Pennac. J'avais oublié toute l'intrigue et l'explication finalement assez glauque derrière les explosions dans le magasin.</comments>
	</book>
     <book>
        <date>2024-12-15</date>
        <title>La fin de la conversation ?</title>
        <subtitle>La parole dans une société spectrale</subtitle>
        <author>David Le Breton</author>
        <publishingyear>2024</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.5</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/208432021</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Le second et probablement dernier livre de Le Breton que je lis. J'aurais probablement dû relire ce que j'avais pensé du premier livre que j'avais lu de lui... Ça se répète quand même beaucoup. On est dans la généralité. Il y a peu de nuances. Et surtout peu de pistes de réflexion, de solution. A part... marcher ?</comments>
        <image>La fin de la conversation.jpg</image>
    </book>
	<book>
        <date>2024-11-30</date>
        <title>Comme un roman</title>
        <author>Daniel Pennac</author>
        <publishingyear>1992</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comme_un_roman</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>C'est la première fois que je relis ce livre depuis 1996. C'est un bon rappel pour moi. Désacraliser la lecture, c'est important. J'ai trop tendance à vouloir lire "utile". Lire des classiques. Il faut que je me donne plus de liberté. C'est aussi l'occasion de lancer une réflexion à propos de notre fils de 6 ans, qui adore qu'on lui lise des livres. Il faut que nous trouvions un moyen de conserver ce rapport enthousiaste qu'il entretient avec les livres. Sans tomber dans les pièges que décrit Pennac (le dogme - "il faut lire").</comments>
        <image>Comme un roman.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2024-11-14</date>
        <title>Les Choses</title>
        <subtitle>Une histoire des années soixante</subtitle>
        <author>Georges Perec</author>
        <publishingyear>1965</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Choses</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Le style de Perec (en tout cas dans ce livre, je ne connais pas les autres) est déconcertant. Il n'y a pas vraiment d'action, d'intrigue, presque uniquement des descriptions. Pas de dialogue non plus. Les longues énumérations sont fréquentes. Toute la partie consacrée à Sfax est spéciale également. Je l'ai lue/ressentie comme une sorte de rêve.</comments>
        <image>Les Choses.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2024-10-17</date>
        <title>Bonjour tristesse</title>
        <author>Françoise Sagan</author>
        <publishingyear>1954</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bonjour_tristesse</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>J'étais familier avec le titre de ce roman, mais je n'en connaissais rien. Une lecture très prenante. Une belle écriture. Une histoire qui me touche néanmoins relativement peu.</comments>
        <image>Bonjour tristesse.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2024-09-23</date>
        <title>L'Homme qui plantait des arbres</title>
        <author>Jean Giono</author>
        <publishingyear>1953</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Homme_qui_plantait_des_arbres</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Un très court récit. J'en avais besoin, après <i>Les Frères Karamazov</i>. Cela m'a aussi fait du bien de lire quelque chose d'aussi positif. C'est une parabole, mais l'idée même de planter des arbres, en soi, est captivante. Je devrais le faire aussi. Littéralement, comme figurativement.</comments>
        <image>L'Homme qui plantait des arbres.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2024-09-19</date>
        <title>Les Frères Karamazov</title>
        <author>Fiodor Dostoïevski</author>
        <publishingyear>1879</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Fr%C3%A8res_Karamazov</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Un classique. Un long livre. Je dois admettre que j'ai eu un peu de peine à le lire. A coup de 10-15 minutes par soir, ça n'était pas suffisant. C'est vraiment lorsque j'ai commencé à dédier de plus grandes tranches de temps à ce livre que j'ai pu véritablement entrer dans le récit. La partie dédié au procès est captivante.</comments>
        <image>Les Frères Karamazov.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2024-02-11</date>
        <title>The Sweet Spot</title>
        <subtitle>The Pleasures of Suffering and the Search for Meaning</subtitle>
        <author>Paul Bloom</author>
        <publishingyear>2021</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/56922622</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>There's a subtle relationship between suffering, meaning, and happiness. I still don't know what it is, but I guess this book is raising a few useful questions. To quote The Guardian: "Bloom endorses motivational pluralism: we're all a tangled mess of complicated drives and enthusiasms, and finding the sweet spot that includes just the right mix of suffering and value and satisfaction is, as the book's subtitle puts it, the "key to a good life"."</comments>
        <image>The Sweet Spot.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2023-12-20</date>
        <title>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland</title>
        <author>Lewis Carroll</author>
        <publishingyear>1865</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60671823</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>It's difficult not to think about Disney's interpretation of the story. The book is quite different. Probably weirder.</comments>
        <image>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2023-12-01</date>
        <title>Outlive</title>
        <subtitle>The Science and Art of Longevity</subtitle>
        <author>Peter Attia</author>
        <publishingyear>2023</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61153739</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>I've been listening to Peter Attia's podcast for 4 years now. I like his rather conservative approach to longevity. My personal takeaway is that I should exercise way more and eat more protein.</comments>
        <image>Outlive.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2023-08-27</date>
        <title>Die With Zero</title>
        <subtitle>Getting All You Can from Your Money and Your Life</subtitle>
        <author>Bill Perkins</author>
        <publishingyear>2020</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52950915</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>I started reading Perkins' book after hearing him on Peter Attia's podcast. Basically, this is a rich guy telling other people to spend more money, earlier in life. He makes some good points, I guess. Invest in experiences and people. Don't plan to do too many things when you're retired, as people's health get worse rather quickly. He's not wrong, but those are not very original ideas. His most interesting idea is that you should really think about the rest of your life and how you're going to spend your money. And maybe - maybe! - you're saving too much money, even if you're not rich. Maybe. I'm not convinced, as I don't live on a yacht, but I'll think about it.</comments>
        <image>Die With Zero.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2023-08-05</date>
        <title>Algorithms to Live By</title>
        <subtitle>The Computer Science of Human Decisions</subtitle>
        <author>Brian Christian &amp; Tom Griffiths</author>
        <publishingyear>2016</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25666050</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>I have a master in computer science, so I often think about the world in terms of algorithms. Some of them are useful on a day-to-day basis. Some of them are useful to better understand the world (so more in a philosophical way, almost). Some of the more advanced concepts coming from machine learning, for example. This book made me realize that there are more links than expected between computer science and the "real world".</comments>
        <image>Algorithms to Live By.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2023-05-31</date>
        <title>Le Dernier Jour d’un condamné</title>
        <author>Victor Hugo</author>
        <publishingyear>1832</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Dernier_Jour_d%27un_condamn%C3%A9</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Un livre absolument fascinant et en avance sur son temps, puisqu'il a fallu attendre presque 150 ans pour que la peine de mort soit enfin abolie en France.</comments>
        <image>Le Dernier Jour d’un condamné.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2023-05-07</date>
        <title>So Long, and Thanks for All the Fish</title>
        <author>Douglas Adams</author>
        <publishingyear>1984</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/So_Long,_and_Thanks_for_All_the_Fish</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>Surprisingly quite boring compared to the previous books in the <i>The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy</i> franchise.</comments>
        <image>So Long, and Thanks for All the Fish.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2023-03-21</date>
        <title>Deep Work</title>
        <subtitle>Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World</subtitle>
        <author>Cal Newport</author>
        <publishingyear>2016</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25744928</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments>An important book at this point in my life. I've been implementing Getting Things Done (GTD) for more than 15 years now and I think I've come to terms with the idea that our time is limited (see <a href="https://olivier.bruchez.name/books#2022-01-29"><i>Four Thousand Weeks</i></a> and <a href="https://olivier.bruchez.name/books#2023-01-28"><i>Midlife</i></a>, for example). The logical conclusion is that we should have a clear set of priorities for all the domains/projects in our lives (e.g. it should be quite clear to anybody that health and the people you love should be at the top of your list) and that when you decide to do something, you should do it with intention and focus, hence the idea that deep work is important. As Newport explains in his book, deep work doesn't come without any effort. You have to decide that you want to work deeply and then make it possible to do it, with strategies such as time blocking, scheduling your days, quitting social networks, etc.</comments>
        <image>Deep Work.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2023-01-28</date>
        <title>Midlife</title>
        <subtitle>A Philosophical Guide</subtitle>
        <author>Kieran Setiya</author>
        <publishingyear>2017</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=fvSnDgAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Midlife (Kieran Setiya).md</notes>
        <comments>A way better book than Christopher Hamilton's <i>Middle Age</i>, with some relatively actionable pieces of advice.</comments>
        <image>Midlife.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-12-29</date>
        <title>The Like Switch</title>
        <subtitle>An Ex-FBI Agent's Guide to Influencing, Attracting, and Winning People Over</subtitle>
        <author>Jack Schafer &amp; Marvin Karlins</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=KKoVBgAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Like Switch (Jack Schafer &amp; Marvin Karlins).md</notes>
        <comments>Part of this book contains useful tips to be more friendly to other people (nonverbal cues, showing empathy, etc.). The rest looks like a guide to become a spy.</comments>
        <image>The Like Switch.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-11-03</date>
        <title>Heaven and Hell</title>
        <author>Aldous Huxley</author>
        <publishingyear>1956</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heaven_and_Hell_(essay)</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Heaven and Hell (Aldous Huxley).md</notes>
        <comments>An essay included along with <i>The Doors of Perception</i>. I found it to be a bit more accessible.</comments>
        <image>Heaven and Hell.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-10-31</date>
        <title>The Doors of Perception</title>
        <author>Aldous Huxley</author>
        <publishingyear>1954</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Doors_of_Perception</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Doors of Perception (Aldous Huxley).md</notes>
        <comments>An intriguing book. A very intellectual take on a mescaline trip, among other topics. Again, I'm not a fan of Huxley's writing. I don't know why exactly.</comments>
        <image>The Doors of Perception.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-09-30</date>
        <title>Brave New World</title>
        <author>Aldous Huxley</author>
        <publishingyear>1932</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brave_New_World</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Brave New World (Aldous Huxley).md</notes>
        <comments>It's a classic, but for some reasons I found it very hard to enjoy it. Maybe the vocabulary is harder to understand for non-native English readers than in most books? I don't know. I had to read a summary of the story half-way through to get an idea of what was happening.</comments>
        <image>Brave New World.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-08-04</date>
        <title>Le Joueur d'échecs</title>
        <author>Stefan Zweig</author>
        <publishingyear>1943</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Joueur_d%27%C3%A9checs</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Le Joueur d'échecs (Stefan Zweig).md</notes>
        <comments>Un très court roman qui m'a vraiment tenu en haleine. Pratiquant la méditation, j'ai par contre été (un peu) amusé par le peu de tolérance à l'ennui du mystérieux personnage du joueur d'échec, pour qui le quotidien dans sa chambre d'hôtel était intolérable. Je ne dis pas que j'aurais été insensible au manque de divertissements, mais la manière dont il décrit ces moments-là m'interpelle.</comments>
        <image>Le Joueur d'échecs.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-07-31</date>
        <title>Everything Is Fucked</title>
        <subtitle>A Book About Hope</subtitle>
        <author>Mark Manson</author>
        <publishingyear>2019</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Everything_Is_Fucked</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Everything Is Fucked (Mark Manson).md</notes>
        <comments>Coming from quite a different angle (meditation, etc.), Sam Harris also thinks that hope is not as positive as we think. It's basically wanting things to be different than what they are, which is often actually a negative thing.</comments>
        <image>Everything Is Fucked.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-06-19</date>
        <title>Animal Farm</title>
        <author>George Orwell</author>
        <publishingyear>1945</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Farm</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Animal Farm (George Orwell).md</notes>
        <comments>Another (short) classic I hadn't read yet. I don't know why, but I expected it to be a book for children. I was pleasantly surprised to discover what it really is (i.e. a critique of political systems).</comments>
        <image>Animal Farm.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-05-28</date>
        <title>Les Rêveries du promeneur solitaire</title>
        <author>Jean-Jacques Rousseau</author>
        <publishingyear>1782</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_R%C3%AAveries_du_promeneur_solitaire</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Les Rêveries du promeneur solitaire (Jean-Jacques Rousseau).md</notes>
        <comments>Ne connaissant rien à Rousseau, j'ai mis du temps à entrer dans cette œuvre, en particulier à cause des passages traitant de la persécution dont Rousseau disait être victime (on a rapidement l'impression qu'il y a là une certaine paranoïa). Les différents chapitres ("promenades") sont autant de thèmes distincts qui sont abordés et on se prend rapidement à un jeu qui consiste à se demander de quoi Rousseau va ensuite parler. Éléments biographiques, retraite sur l'Île Saint-Pierre, réflexions philosophiques (qu'est-ce que le mensonge ?), passion pour la nature et la botanique, etc. sont autant de sujets abordés.</comments>
        <image>Les Rêveries du promeneur solitaire.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-04-08</date>
        <title>Wanting</title>
        <subtitle>The Power of Mimetic Desire in Everyday Life</subtitle>
        <author>Luke Burgis</author>
        <publishingyear>2021</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=9ty-zQEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Wanting (Luke Burgis).md</notes>
        <comments>A book about <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mimetic_theory">mimetic theory</a>.</comments>
        <image>Wanting.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-02-11</date>
        <title>Jacques et son maître</title>
        <subtitle>Hommage à Denis Diderot en trois actes</subtitle>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1981</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=FjHIAAAACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Jacques et son maître (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>Une variation, au sens musical du terme, de <i>Jacques le Fataliste et son maître</i>, l'un des romans préférés de Kundera. Avec cette pièce de théâtre, plutôt divertissante, j'ai terminé de lire les oeuvres "officielles" de Kundera, c'est-à-dire les oeuvres qu'il reconnaît lui-même comme dignes d'intérêt, le reste n'ayant pas été réédité ou traduit. Je suis prêt pour le prochain livre de Kundera, qu'il est, je l'espère, en train d'écrire malgré son âge avancé.</comments>
        <image>Jacques et son maître.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2022-01-29</date>
        <title>Four Thousand Weeks</title>
        <subtitle>Time Management for Mortals</subtitle>
        <author>Oliver Burkeman</author>
        <publishingyear>2021</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=WFP2DwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Four Thousand Weeks (Oliver Burkeman).md</notes>
        <comments>This is a book I <i>really</i> needed to read right now. I tend to commit to too many projects, without completing any of them, which causes anxiety/stress. Life is short/finite. We all have too many things to do compared to the time we have, so we have to get our priorities straight and commit to one important project at a time.</comments>
        <image>Four Thousand Weeks.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2021-12-30</date>
        <title>L'Immortalité</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1988</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Immortalit%C3%A9</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">L'Immortalité (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>Un roman rempli de thèmes qui me touchent : la musique, la pollution sonore (les motos, etc.), la pollution visuelle (les voitures dans les villes), le concept de chemin (qui permet une forme de méditation en marche) vs celui de route (qui permet d'aller d'un point A à un point B), vivre vs être (encore un appel à la méditation au sens moderne du terme, bien que Kundera ne semble pas très familier avec le concept), etc. Kundera oppose toujours assez naïvement la "grande musique" (i.e. la musique classique) et la "musique rock". C'est son côté vieux con, qui me plaît bien, au final. Je prends encore une fois conscience que les romans de Kundera sont difficiles à résumer. Les personnages se croisent. Le récit n'est pas linéaire. Les parenthèses sont nombreuses. Chacune d'entre elle est l'occasion de s'arrêter, de se questionner, de contempler. Oui, il y a définitivement un appel à la méditation et à la contemplation chez Kundera.</comments>
        <image>L'Immortalité.jpg</image>
    </book> 
    <book>
        <date>2021-11-25</date>
        <title>Fahrenheit 451</title>
        <author>Ray Bradbury</author>
        <publishingyear>1953</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fahrenheit_451</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Fahrenheit 451 (Ray Bradbury).md</notes>
        <comments>A classic I hadn't read yet. I don't know why, but it evoked eerie and dream-like images in my mind, instead of futuristic ones. I could see David Lynch working on an adaptation. Strangely, it was François Truffaut who directed <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0060390/">an adaptation of it in 1966</a>, which I'll probably see soon, out of curiosity.</comments>
        <image>Fahrenheit 451.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2021-10-29</date>
        <title>Le Nom de la rose</title>
        <author>Umberto Eco</author>
        <publishingyear>1980</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Nom_de_la_rose_(roman)</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Le Nom de la rose (Umberto Eco).md</notes>
        <comments>I watched the movie a long time ago (probably in the 90s). I still remember some aspects of it, which influenced my reading (e.g. picturing William of Baskerville as Sean Connery...). The book itself is brilliant, full of long parts about specific elements, such as a dream Adso had, inspired by the Coena Cypriani, which I really liked (it's very Rabelaisesque at times). Probably a book I'll read again in the future.</comments>
        <image>Le Nom de la rose.jpg</image>
    </book> 
    <book>
        <date>2021-08-03</date>
        <title>Prince and the Parade and Sign O' The Times Era Studio Sessions: 1985 and 1986</title>
        <author>Duane Tudhal</author>
        <publishingyear>2021</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=zJ4qEAAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Prince and the Parade and Sign O' The Times Era Studio Sessions - 1985 and 1986 (Duane Tudahl).md</notes>
        <comments>A brilliant book, even better than the previous one. I could almost copy-paste my comments for the book about 1983-84. At the time, I concluded: "He was a really hard-working artist." Yes, Prince was a genius, but he was also very lonely. And weird. It's quite obvious that he worked so much because he didn't really know what to do when not playing music. I hope more books will be released, especially about the 1987-88 years.</comments>
        <image>Prince and the Parade and Sign O' The Times Era Studio Sessions - 1985 and 1986.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2021-06-16</date>
        <title>Radical Compassion</title>
        <subtitle>Learning to Love Yourself and Your World with the Practice of RAIN</subtitle>
        <author>Tara Brach</author>
        <publishingyear>2020</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=2yWHDwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Radical Compassion (Tara Brach).md</notes>
        <comments>I'm quite convinced by the <a href="https://www.tarabrach.com/rain-practice-radical-compassion/">RAIN method</a> described in this book, which itself was quite average (i.e. too long for the actual amount of information it contains).</comments>
        <image>Radical Compassion.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2021-05-24</date>
        <title>Consolations</title>
        <subtitle>The Solace, Nourishment and Underlying Meaning of Everyday Words</subtitle>
        <author>David Whyte</author>
        <publishingyear>2014</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=7BC3rQEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Consolations (David Whyte).md</notes>
        <comments>My second David Whyte collection. I really like his writing. I'm also currently listening to him reading his essays in Sam Harris' Waking Up app.</comments>
        <image>Consolations.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2021-05-05</date>
        <title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title>
        <author>Ted Chiang</author>
        <publishingyear>2002</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stories_of_Your_Life_and_Others</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Stories of Your Life and Others (Ted Chiang).md</notes>
        <comments>Another excellent short stories collection. The movie <i>Arrival</i>, which I really like, was based on one of those stories. The only frustrating thing is that I've now apparently read pretty much everything Ted Chiang ever wrote...</comments>
        <image>Stories of Your Life and Others.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2021-04-30</date>
        <title>The Joys and Sorrows of Parenting</title>
        <subtitle>26 Essays to Reassure and Console</subtitle>
        <author>The School of Life</author>
        <publishingyear>2019</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=gLT1twEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Joys and Sorrows of Parenting (The School of Life).md</notes>
        <comments>A bit too short/light, but not bad. I should probably read some of those essays again from time to time.</comments>
        <image>The Joys and Sorrows of Parenting.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2021-03-09</date>
        <title>La vie est ailleurs</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1969</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_vie_est_ailleurs</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">La vie est ailleurs (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>J'ai lu ce livre il y a 21 ans. Je ne m'en souvenais quasiment plus du tout. Un roman réussi à propos de la poésie, du communisme, de l'art, de la politique, de l'amour (y compris maternel), etc. J'ai bien aimé les passages oniriques, en particulier au début. Ce mélange rêve/réalité - qu'est-ce que la réalité ? - est aussi un thème/style que j'apprécie chez David Lynch.</comments>
        <image>La vie est ailleurs.jpg</image>
    </book> 
    <book>
        <date>2021-02-07</date>
        <title>MDMA solo</title>
        <author>Phoenix Kaspian</author>
        <publishingyear>2020</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.0</rating>
        <url>https://castaliafoundation.com/</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">MDMA solo (Phoenix Kaspian).md</notes>
        <comments>This was a weird read. There are some good things in this book, obviously inspired by the Internal Family System (IFS) model and <i>Self-Therapy</i> book, but it sounds like it was written by someone who's really paranoid and anti-authority.</comments>
        <image>MDMA solo.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2021-01-15</date>
        <title>Exhalation: Stories</title>
        <author>Ted Chiang</author>
        <publishingyear>2019</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exhalation:_Stories</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Exhalation - Stories (Ted Chiang).md</notes>
        <comments>I discovered Ted Chiang thanks to the Very Bad Wizards podcast. This is the kind of science fiction I like. I've already bought another collection, <i>Stories of Your Life and Others</i>.</comments>
        <image>Exhalation - Stories.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-11-27</date>
        <title>La Valse aux adieux</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1972</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Valse_aux_adieux</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">La Valse aux adieux (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>J'ai eu un peu de peine à entrer dans ce roman. Puis on se laisse emmener par ces destins croisés, par ces personnages dont la destinée leur échappe.</comments>
        <image>La Valse aux adieux.jpg</image>
    </book> 
    <book>
        <date>2020-10-12</date>
        <title>Lifespan</title>
        <subtitle>Why We Age – and Why We Don't Have To</subtitle>
        <author>David Andrew Sinclair</author>
        <publishingyear>2019</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lifespan:_Why_We_Age_%E2%80%93_and_Why_We_Don%27t_Have_To</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Lifespan (David Andrew Sinclair).md</notes>
        <comments>I was already familiar with David's ideas and discoveries. You basically just need to watch a few YouTube videos to learn about them. I was especially curious about his views on how humanity will have to adapt to longer lifespans/healthspans and that part of the book somewhat disappointed me. Not all my concerns were addressed. In particular, automation/machine learning and the facts that a lot of jobs will really disappear at some point, without new jobs to replace them, the need for some form of universal basic income, and the fact that, mathematically, even if we still die, the world population will really become problematic at some point if we keep having children (maybe not in 100 or 200 years, but still). I recently heard David in a podcast briefly mention the fact that human beings will have to find a way to go to other planets in the future (or something to that effect). I guess that's what I expected to read in his book. But he wanted to stay optimistic, so he focused on the near-term future, I guess.</comments>
        <image>Lifespan.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-09-06</date>
        <title>The Art of Living</title>
        <subtitle>Self-management - How to Survive and Thrive in the 21st Century</subtitle>
        <author>Youssef El Baba</author>
        <publishingyear>2020</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.5</rating>
        <url>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52431581-the-art-of-living</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Art of Living (Youssef El Baba).md</notes>
        <comments>This book convinced me that it's time to migrate from my current system (based on G Suite) to a more specific tool (maybe Omnifocus - I was not convinced by 2Do).</comments>
        <image>The Art of Living.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-07-14</date>
        <title>A Brief History of Time</title>
        <subtitle>From the Big Bang to Black Holes</subtitle>
        <author>Stephen Hawking</author>
        <publishingyear>1988</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Brief_History_of_Time</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">A Brief History of Time (Stephen Hawking).md</notes>
        <comments>I don't know why, but I expected something overly-simplified (not to say dumbed-down). Something I could understand. :) I was somewhat surprised to discover that this book tries to explain very hard concepts in a relatively simple way, which still leads to... a complex book with very complex concepts. I don't think you could say it's highly accessible. Which makes me wonder whether anybody could do better than Hawking. I'm not saying he failed. Popularizing science is really hard. I'm just saying I was a bit disappointed.</comments>
        <image>A Brief History of Time.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-05-27</date>
        <title>L'Identité</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1995</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Identit%C3%A9</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">L'Identité (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>Étrange passage de la réalité au rêve, autour de la thématique de l'identité et de ses frontières. L'essai suivant le texte est très éclairant.</comments>
        <image>L'Identité.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020.05.11</date>
        <title>The Carpet People</title>
        <author>Terry Pratchett</author>
        <publishingyear>1992</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Carpet_People</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Carpet People (Terry Pratchett).md</notes>
        <comments>My first book by Terry Pratchett. I've heard a lot about him, but I'm not sure if I'm a fan of his style (granted, this is probably not his most representative book).</comments>
        <image>The Carpet People.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-04-15</date>
        <title>Life, the Universe and Everything</title>
        <author>Douglas Adams</author>
        <publishingyear>1982</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Life,_the_Universe_and_Everything</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Life, the Universe and Everything (Douglas Adams).md</notes>
        <comments>I particularly liked the part where Arthur discovered he could fly.</comments>
        <image>Life, the Universe and Everything.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-04-10</date>
        <title>Capitale de la douleur</title>
        <author>Paul Éluard</author>
        <publishingyear>1926</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capitale_de_la_douleur</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Capitale de la douleur (Paul Éluard).md</notes>
        <comments>C'est certainement très bon, mais ça ne m'a absolument pas touché. Je dois manquer des clés nécessaires pour comprendre ce genre de poésie.</comments>
        <image>Capitale de la douleur.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-03-30</date>
        <title>Une rencontre</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>2009</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Une_rencontre</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Une rencontre (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments><i>Une rencontre</i> ou <i>Si Milan Kundera avait un blog</i>... Kundera parle de compositeurs, peintres et écrivains/romanciers qui l'ont influencé. C'est toujours très bien écrit, mais ça m'a moins touché, ne connaissant pas la plupart des artistes qu'il mentionne.</comments>
        <image>Une rencontre.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-03-24</date>
        <title>David Whyte: Essentials</title>
        <author>David Whyte</author>
        <publishingyear>2019</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=2cq2ywEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">David Whyte - Essentials (David Whyte).md</notes>
        <comments>I discovered David Whyte in February 2020. I liked his discussion with Sam Harris on the Making Sense podcast. This is the kind of poetry I like. I think.</comments>
        <image>David Whyte - Essentials.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-03-24</date>
        <title>Jacques le Fataliste et son maître</title>
        <author>Denis Diderot</author>
        <publishingyear>1796</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jacques_le_Fataliste_et_son_ma%C3%AEtre</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Jacques le Fataliste et son maître (Denis Diderot).md</notes>
        <comments>C'est un hasard, mais c'est une œuvre très similaire à <i>Candide</i>, à savoir un "classique pas du tout ennuyeux", très libre dans sa structure (interruptions répétées des récits, discussions imaginaires entre l'auteur et le lecteur, etc.). On est encore relativement proche de Rabelais. Ça se lit très facilement. C'est à la fois léger et intelligent.</comments>
        <image>Jacques le Fataliste et son maître.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-02-29</date>
        <title>The Great Gatsby</title>
        <author>F. Scott Fitzgerald</author>
        <publishingyear>1925</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Great_Gatsby</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Great Gatsby (F. Scott Fitzgerald).md</notes>
        <comments>I saw the 2013 movie and really liked it. The book is a classic, but it didn't manage to impress me as much.</comments>
        <image>The Great Gatsby.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-02-17</date>
        <title>Madame Bovary</title>
        <subtitle>Mœurs de province</subtitle>
        <author>Gustave Flaubert</author>
        <publishingyear>1857</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Madame_Bovary</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Madame Bovary (Gustave Flaubert).md</notes>
        <comments>Un vrai classique, au sens où je me l'imagine. Comme <i>Candide</i>, je ne me souviens pas avoir étudié ce livre durant mes études. Je suis content de l'avoir lu avec le recul probablement nécessaire pour l'apprécier. Les longues descriptions typiques de Flaubert ne m'ont pas dérangé. Au contraire, j'ai trouvé son style plutôt impressionnant. Je ne m'étonne pas que l'écriture de cette œuvre ait nécessité plus de quatre ans de la vie de Flaubert.</comments>
        <image>Madame Bovary.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-01-19</date>
        <title>And Then There Were None</title>
        <author>Agatha Christie</author>
        <publishingyear>1939</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/And_Then_There_Were_None</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">And Then There Were None (Agatha Christie).md</notes>
        <comments>Crime novels are not my cup of tea and I'm not sure I will ever read another Agatha Christie books in my life, but I had a lot of fun reading <i>And Then There Were None</i>.</comments>
        <image>And Then There Were None.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2020-01-07</date>
        <title>Candide</title>
        <author>Voltaire</author>
        <publishingyear>1759</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Candide</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Candide (Voltaire).md</notes>
        <comments>Un texte qui se lit très facilement. Je ne me souviens pas l'avoir étudié durant mes études, mais j'ai eu beaucoup de plaisir à le lire. Je le classerais dans la catégorie "classiques pas du tout ennuyeux".</comments>
        <image>Candide.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-12-27</date>
        <title>La Lenteur</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1994</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Lenteur</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">La lenteur (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>J'avais déjà lu ce livre, mais je ne me souvenais absolument pas de l'histoire, à part la scène de la piscine. Kundera mène une réflexion sur le monde moderne et, en particulier, sur le rôle des <i>mass media</i> (c'était avant l'apparition d'internet) et celui de la vitesse / de la lenteur dans l'oubli / la mémoire et l'Histoire. Il fait un parallèle avec <a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Point_de_lendemain"><i>Point de lendemain</i></a> de Vivant Denon, démystifie un peu l'épicurisme (qui parle de plaisirs simples, pas de débauche, comme on pourrait le croire) et condamne ces "danseurs" qui font ce qu'on a appelé bien plus tard du <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtue_signalling"><i>virtue signalling</i></a>.</comments>
        <image>La Lenteur.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-12-21</date>
        <title>How to Worry Less about Money</title>
        <author>John Armstrong</author>
        <publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=g7OxpwAACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">How to Worry Less about Money (John Armstrong).md</notes>
        <comments>Not a self-help book. Like <i>The Consolations of Philosophy</i>, it's a book that uses philosophy to give us a new perspective on a topic.</comments>
        <image>How to Worry Less about Money.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-12-19</date>
        <title>The Beautiful Ones</title>
        <author>Prince Rogers Nelson &amp; Dan Piepenbring</author>
        <publishingyear>2019</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=AWKSDwAAQBAJ</url>
        <comments>Prince died a few months after starting to work on this project. It is what it is and I must say that Dan Piepenbring did a great job with what he had.</comments>
        <image>The Beautiful Ones.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-12-11</date>
        <title>L'Art du roman</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1986</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Art_du_roman</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">L'art du roman (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>Un regard critique et sophistiqué de l'auteur sur son oeuvre, sur la structure de ses romans, sur le rôle du roman en général, sur le lien entre l'écriture et la musique, sur l'exercice compliqué de la traduction, etc.</comments>
        <image>L'Art du roman.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-11-21</date>
        <title>Self-Therapy</title>
        <subtitle>A Step-By-Step Guide to Creating Inner Wholeness Using IFS, a New, Cutting-Edge Therapy</subtitle>
        <author>Jay Earley</author>
        <publishingyear>2009</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=Ny96Z7N_ihsC</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Self-Therapy (Jay Earley).md</notes>
        <comments>At first, IFS kind of sounded like woo to me, but after a while, it started to make sense. I think I like this approach. It's almost like an algorithm. It's also somewhat related to meditation in general and to loving kindness meditation in particular. I'm going to try it.</comments>
        <image>Self-Therapy.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-11-16</date>
        <title>Poèmes saturniens</title>
        <author>Paul Verlaine</author>
        <publishingyear>1866</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Po%C3%A8mes_saturniens</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Poèmes saturniens (Paul Verlaine).md</notes>
        <comments>Je n'ai pas accroché. Je crois qu'il va falloir que je m'éloigne un peu des classiques pour que je trouve de la poésie qui me touche vraiment.</comments>
        <image>Poèmes saturniens.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-10-02</date>
        <title>La Métamorphose</title>
        <author>Franz Kafka</author>
        <publishingyear>1915</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_M%C3%A9tamorphose</url>
        <comments>J'avais lu des extraits de ce livre en allemand il y a 25 ans, mais je crois ne l'avoir jamais lu en entier jusqu'à présent. Il s'agit ici de la première traduction, celle d'Alexandre Vialatte (apparemment problématique, mais tant pis). <i>La Métamorphose</i> est un texte très prenant, à la fois triste et révoltant, qui nous invite à un peu plus d'humanité.</comments>
        <image>La Métamorphose.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-09-17</date>
        <title>Happy</title>
        <subtitle>Why More or Less Everything is Absolutely Fine</subtitle>
        <author>Derren Brown</author>
        <publishingyear>2016</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=4lB8DAAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Happy (Derren Brown).md</notes>
        <comments>A pretty good book about stoicism (mainly) and death. Reading <i>A Guide to the Good Life</i> by William B. Irvine was what led me to stoicism as a philosophy of life. <i>Happy</i> takes all those ideas from stoicism and confronts them with real life. It could have been shorter, but it's full of good advice. I guess it's a self-help book, but in the good sense of the word. Realizing that you can't control everything, that you have to prepare for death (both others' and your own), etc. is hard. So, yes, being happy is hard work. You can't just "think positively". That won't work. Bad things will happen. All the time. You have to learn how to react accordingly. The only thing I didn't agree with was Brown's argument that immortality would necessarily be boring. It kind of contradicts the fact that you can learn to not find anything boring (e.g. meditation). But this is a minor point.</comments>
        <image>Happy.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-08-06</date>
        <title>The Restaurant at the End of the Universe</title>
        <author>Douglas Adams</author>
        <publishingyear>1980</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Restaurant_at_the_End_of_the_Universe</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Restaurant at the End of the Universe (Douglas Adams).md</notes>
        <comments>A good sequel to <i>The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy</i>.</comments>
        <image>The Restaurant at the End of the Universe.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-07-12</date>
        <title>Conscious</title>
        <subtitle>A Brief Guide to the Fundamental Mystery of the Mind</subtitle>
        <author>Annaka Harris</author>
        <publishingyear>2019</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=k4hRuwEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Conscious (Annaka Harris).md</notes>
        <comments>A good summary of the problem of consciousness. And, yes, panpsychism is probably worth investigating.</comments>
        <image>Conscious.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-06-23</date>
        <title>The Consolations of Philosophy</title>
        <author>Alain de Botton</author>
        <publishingyear>2000</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Consolations_of_Philosophy</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Consolations of Philosophy (Alain de Botton).md</notes>
        <comments>I was familiar with Alain de Botton's YouTube videos (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/schooloflifechannel">The School of Life</a>). I've never been completely convinced by his approach. Is this self-help? Pop philosophy? Something else? I don't know. I'm still not convinced.</comments>
        <image>The Consolations of Philosophy.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-06-20</date>
        <title>The Ones Who Walk Away from Omelas</title>
        <author>Ursula K. Le Guin</author>
        <publishingyear>1973</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Ones_Who_Walk_Away_from_Omelas</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Ones Who Walk Away from Omelas (Ursula K. Le Guin).md</notes>
        <comments>A very short text. I read it after listening to the Very Bad Wizards episode about it. The vagueness of the story reminds me a bit of Jorge Luis Borges.</comments>
        <image>The Ones Who Walk Away from Omelas.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-05-21</date>
        <title>It Doesn't Have to Be Crazy at Work</title>
        <author>Jason Fried &amp; David Heinemeier Hansson</author>
        <publishingyear>2018</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=aOlMDwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">It Doesn't Have to Be Crazy at Work (Jason Fried &amp; David Heinemeier Hansson).md</notes>
        <comments>Not bad. It's like a collection of blog posts. Or a big advertisement for Basecamp. Anyway, a lot of the advice found in this book should be common sense. But it's not, unfortunately.</comments>
        <image>It Doesn't Have to Be Crazy at Work.jpg</image>
    </book> 
    <book>
        <date>2019-05-08</date>
        <title>L'Ecclésiaste</title>
        <subtitle>Un temps pour tout</subtitle>
        <author>Ernest Renan</author>
        <publishingyear>1881</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eccl%C3%A9siaste</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">L'Ecclésiaste (Ernest Renan).md</notes>
        <comments>Texte original et étude/commentaire d'Ernest Renan. Le livre en lui-même, faisant partie de la Bible, est court. Le commentaire est nettement plus long, mais pas vraiment "à mon goût". <a href="https://sites.libsyn.com/474285/episode-160-everything-is-meaningless-the-book-of-ecclesiastes">L'approche irrévérencieuse de Dave et Tamler du podcast Very Bad Wizards</a> correspondait plus à ma sensibilité (athée, donc).</comments>
        <image>L'Ecclésiaste.jpg</image>
    </book> 
    <book>
        <date>2019-04-23</date>
        <title>Le Livre du rire et de l'oubli</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1979</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Livre_du_rire_et_de_l%27oubli</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Le Livre du rire et de l'oubli (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>Un livre de Kundera plus inégal, pour moi. On y trouve toujours des passages géniaux et ce mélange entre la fiction, l'essai et l'autobiographie. Et puis, il y a des moments plus confus. Plus étranges. Comme le passage de l'île aux enfants. Je crois que je comprends les éléments allégoriques, mais ça reste malsain. Tout du moins en contraste avec le reste du livre.</comments>
        <image>Le Livre du rire et de l'oubli.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-03-29</date>
        <title>Why We Sleep</title>
        <subtitle>The New Science of Sleep and Dreams</subtitle>
        <author>Matthew Walker</author>
        <publishingyear>2017</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Why_We_Sleep</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Why We Sleep (Matthew Walker).md</notes>
        <comments>Summary: we should all sleep more. Lack of sleep is bad for... pretty much everything. See also <a href="https://medlineplus.gov/magazine/issues/summer12/articles/summer12pg20.html">Tips for Getting a Good Night's Sleep</a>. 2021-04-05: see <a href="https://guzey.com/books/why-we-sleep/">Matthew Walker's "Why We Sleep" Is Riddled with Scientific and Factual Errors</a>.</comments>
        <image>Why We Sleep.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2019-02-19</date>
        <title>Voyage au bout de la nuit</title>
        <author>Louis-Ferdinand Céline</author>
        <publishingyear>1932</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voyage_au_bout_de_la_nuit</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Voyage au bout de la nuit (Céline).md</notes>
        <comments>Un classique, sur lequel tout a été écrit, par moments un peu difficile à lire à cause du langage parlé (peu de ponctuation, phrases longues, etc.). Il est difficile de ne pas se laisser emmener dans ce voyage un peu fou, souvent sombre, du narrateur, Bardamu, ce anti-héros auquel on finit par s'attacher - un peu, parfois.</comments>
        <image>Voyage au bout de la nuit.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-12-31</date>
        <title>Sapiens</title>
        <subtitle>A Brief History of Humankind</subtitle>
        <author>Yuval Noah Harari</author>
        <publishingyear>2014</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sapiens:_A_Brief_History_of_Humankind</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Sapiens (Yuval Noah Harari).md</notes>
        <comments>I really enjoyed <i>Homo Deus</i> and since it looks like half of the world has already read <i>Sapiens</i>, I had to read it as well! This is not your usual history book. Harari is strongly opinionated. I'm still bothered by his use of some words (e.g. "religion" for "ideology"), but liked the book nevertheless. It's a bit oversimplistic at times (it especially struck me at the end of the book, where Harari is talking about genetic algorithms and computer viruses), but overall I liked Harari's high-level approach to the subject. For reference: <a href="https://danielmiessler.com/projects/reading/summary-sapiens/">Daniel Miessler's summary of the book</a>.</comments>
        <image>Sapiens.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-11-08</date>
        <title>Ethics in the Real World</title>
        <subtitle>82 Brief Essays on Things That Matter</subtitle>
        <author>Peter Singer</author>
        <publishingyear>2016</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com?id=P4f8CwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Ethics in the Real World (Peter Singer).md</notes>
        <comments>This is the first book by Peter Singer that I've read. It's probably not his best or most well-known book, but I wanted something recent, that was not completely about effective altruism or animal rights (I'm already convinced in both cases), and that would show me how he thinks. As an introduction to his work, I think it's a great book. It's also very easy to read, as it's composed of 82 independent essays (grouped by theme).</comments>
        <image>Ethics in the Real World.png</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-11-05</date>
        <title>How to Change Your Mind</title>
        <subtitle>What the New Science of Psychedelics Teaches Us About Consciousness, Dying, Addiction, Depression, and Transcendence</subtitle>
        <author>Michael Pollan</author>
        <publishingyear>2018</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com?id=3vk5DwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">How to Change Your Mind (Michael Pollan).md</notes>
        <comments><i>The Psychedelic Explorer's Guide</i> was disappointing. This book is way better. It's good journalism. Apart from a tiny bit of quantum mysticism (?) at the end, I found it very critical, informative, and easy to read. The structure of the book is really clear (probably as much as the structure of <i>The Psychedelic Explorer's Guide</i> was confusing). It mentions recent studies, but always from a critical angle. Psychedelics are probably not a panacea, but there really is something to them. We need more research, as soon as possible. We have lost enough time since the late 60s. I'm personally especially curious about microdosing: does it work or is it just a placebo?</comments>
        <image>How to Change Your Mind.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-09-16</date>
        <title>The Last Lecture</title>
        <author>Randy Pausch &amp; Jeffrey Zaslow</author>
        <publishingyear>2008</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Lecture</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Last Lecture (Randy Pausch &amp; Jeffrey Zaslow).md</notes>
        <comments>According to my notes, I watched the lecture on July 26, 2008. Ten years ago; I would have sworn that it was only 5-7 years ago! Still according to my notes, I found the lecture "interesting" and "it made me think a little". I was apparently happy that Randy Pausch didn't make any mention of religion (I was in my "God Delusion phase" at the time, I guess). The book is a kind of a making-of. In 2018, I don't know what to make of it. It's moving. It's kind of impressive (Pausch died three months after the book was published). It's somewhat inspiring. I guess the way Pausch lived his life and especially the end of it is a reminder that life is short (again...) and that we should live our life accordingly.</comments>
        <image>The Last Lecture.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-09-13</date>
        <title>De la brièveté de la vie</title>
        <author>Sénèque</author>
        <publishingyear>2013</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/De_la_bri%C3%A8vet%C3%A9_de_la_vie</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">De la brièveté de la vie (Sénèque).md</notes>
        <comments>Version Presses Électroniques de France. Traducteur inconnu. Un court essai écrit en 49 (il y a 1969 ans !), mais qui est toujours d'actualité (esclavagisme et orgies romaines mis à part). J'imagine que la traduction fait beaucoup, mais le texte semble vraiment beaucoup plus récent.</comments>
        <image>De la brièveté de la vie.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-09-12</date>
        <title>Risibles Amours</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1986</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Risibles_Amours</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Risibles Amours (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>Publié originellement en 1970. Cette traduction a été revue par Kundera. Il s'agit d'un recueil de textes datant d'avant son premier roman. Je ne sais pas si je l'aurais deviné, mais, le sachant, cela a teinté un peu ma lecture et je dois admettre que j'ai moins aimé ces textes que les romans avec lesquels je suis déjà familier. Je n'ai pas retrouvé le Kundera que j'aime bien et qui mêle avec habileté la fiction, ses connaissance de l'histoire, de l'art et de la musique. On a parfois de la peine à voir la limite entre roman et essai, et c'est ce qui me plaît en général chez lui. C'est beaucoup moins le cas dans ce recueil.</comments>
        <image>Risibles Amour.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-09-11</date>
        <title>Lost Connections</title>
        <subtitle>Uncovering the Real Causes of Depression – and the Unexpected Solutions</subtitle>
        <author>Johann Hari</author>
        <publishingyear>2018</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com?id=WIg2DwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Lost Connections (Johann Hari).md</notes>
        <comments>I don't know if many books have been written before about the "non-biochemical" causes of depression and anxiety, but this book gives a far more plausible explanation of depression than the chemical imbalance theory. Antidepressants don't work well (or at all, in many cases), so we need a new way to look at things. We can't always fix our problems by taking pills. Hari gives us at least seven solutions or, rather, potential avenues to explore. They're not quick hacks. They're difficult to implement. Some of them will probably come from larger societal changes and not from individual efforts. I will have to process my notes and see if I can actually do something actionable from them.</comments>
        <image>Lost Connections.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-09-10</date>
        <title>The Psychedelic Explorer's Guide</title>
        <subtitle>Safe, Therapeutic, and Sacred Journeys</subtitle>
        <author>James Fadiman</author>
        <publishingyear>2011</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com?id=CftkAwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Psychedelic Explorer's Guide (James Fadiman).md</notes>
        <comments>An uneven book. It's a collection of texts written by Fadiman, as well as other persons. It doesn't have a clear structure (at least to me). Fadiman believes in God. Not in a personal god, probably, but it's still a bit unsettling. A large part of the book is about the spiritual/mystical aspect of psychedelics. The part about microdosing was far more intriguing. Many studies about psychedelics were done in the 50s/60s and their quality probably leaves a lot to be desired. We need better books about this topic.</comments>
        <image>The Psychedelic Explorer's Guide.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-08-02</date>
        <title>The Library of Babel and Other Stories</title>
        <author>Jorge Luis Borges</author>
        <publishingyear>2017</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com?id=5ZJBDwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Library of Babel and Other Stories (Jorge Luis Borges).md</notes>
        <comments>I got this collection mainly to read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Library_of_Babel">"The Library of Babel"</a>, so that I could listen to the <i>Borges' Babylon</i> episode of Very Bad Wizards. I'll just link to <a href="http://olivier.bruchez.name/podcasts#2018-07-31">my review of the episode</a>. To sum it up: I'm not a fan of Borges (yet). After that, I also read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Garden_of_Forking_Paths">"The Garden of Forking Paths"</a>, from <i>Collected Fictions</i>. I'm still not convinced...</comments>
        <image>The Library of Babel and Other Stories.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-07-17</date>
        <title>Summary: The 4-Hour Body</title>
        <subtitle>An Uncommon Guide to Rapid Fat Loss, Incredible Sex and Becoming Superhuman</subtitle>
        <author>Millionaire Mindset Publishing</author>
        <publishingyear>2017</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com?id=C9qctAEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Summary - The 4-Hour Body (Millionaire Mindset Publishing).md</notes>
        <comments>I'm rating the summary, here, not the original book by Timothy Ferriss. This is the first time I read a non-free summary of a book since my studies. Conclusion: I'm glad I didn't read the way longer book by Timothy Ferriss (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_4-Hour_Body"><i>The 4-Hour Body</i></a>). There are a few interesting pieces of information, maybe even some that will lead me to change something in my life, but this summary confirms what I have been thinking for quite some time: Tim and I are not trying to optimize the same things in our lives; Tim is interested in maximizing performance (and book sales); I'm interested in maximizing health/happiness. Does having more muscle or being able to run a marathon lead to happiness? For some people, certainly. For me? I'm not so sure.</comments>
        <image>Summary - The 4-Hour Body.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-07-15</date>
        <title>Quiet</title>
        <subtitle>The Power of Introverts in a World That Can't Stop Talking</subtitle>
        <author>Susan Cain</author>
        <publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quiet:_The_Power_of_Introverts_in_a_World_That_Can%27t_Stop_Talking</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Quiet (Susan Cain).md</notes>
        <comments>This book will probably help me accept the fact that I am introverted and that it's okay, that I don't have to completely change the way I behave. The book itself is rather good, not great. It would have benefited from less "case studies" (i.e. anecdotes) and a more theoretical approach.</comments>
        <image>Quiet.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-06-09</date>
        <title>Middle Age</title>
        <author>Christopher Hamilton</author>
        <publishingyear>2009</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com?id=_JMSAQAAMAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Middle Age (Christopher Hamilton).md</notes>
        <comments>This is a book about Hamilton's personal experience, with a lot of quotes, which touches a bit on middle age. It's not uninteresting, but it was not what I expected.</comments>
        <image>Middle Age.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-05-11</date>
        <title>Life 3.0</title>
        <subtitle>Being Human in the Age of Artificial Intelligence</subtitle>
        <author>Max Tegmark</author>
        <publishingyear>2017</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Life_3.0</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Life 3.0 (Max Tegmark).md</notes>
        <comments>Having read five books by Ray Kurzweil, I'm quite familiar with artificial intelligence and its consequences. This book focuses on the dangers of AI. Kurzweil was (still is?) an optimist, so it's important to think about what needs to be done, concretely, to make sure we create friendly AIs. To many, it will sound like an exercise in futility (like worrying about overpopulation on Mars, according to Andrew Ng), but I'm now convinced that this is something we really need to get right. And I'm happy that very intelligent people have already been thinking about this problem for years.</comments>
        <image>Life 3.0.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-05-10</date>
        <title>Les Fleurs du mal</title>
        <author>Charles Baudelaire</author>
        <publishingyear>1857</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Fleurs_du_mal</url>
        <comments>Un classique de la poésie. Objectivement, je vois pourquoi il s'agit d'un classique, surtout si on le replace dans le contexte de son époque, mais je ne peux pas dire que beaucoup des poèmes de ce recueil m'aient vraiment touché. Dans un autre style, <i>Paroles</i> de Prévert m'avait paru nettement plus accessible. Cela dit, je n'y connais rien en poésie et il ne s'agit que du deuxième recueil que je lis depuis mes études.</comments>
        <image>Les Fleurs du mal.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-03-29</date>
        <title>Le Rideau</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>2005</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Rideau</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Le Rideau (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>J'ai toujours du plaisir à me plonger dans les essais de Kundera, même si je suis parfois dépassé par toutes les références à des auteurs ou compositeurs qui me sont inconnus. Il a toutefois une manière éclairante de mettre en contexte l'art du roman, ce qui rend ce mode d'expression unique, ce qui le fait traverser les frontières, au-delà des cultures soi-disant nationales. J'aime aussi sa façon de faire des parallèles avec d'autres formes d'art et en particulier avec la musique. Au final, Kundera défend la singularité du roman qui est selon lui seul à pouvoir aussi bien rendre intelligible le monde qui nous entoure, les sociétés, les époques, les évènements historiques, etc., beaucoup plus en interrogeant le monde, la psychologie des personnages, qu'en donnant des réponses toutes faites faisant référence à des systèmes de pensée préexistants.</comments>
        <image>Le Rideau.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-03-10</date>
        <title>The Social Skills Guidebook</title>
        <subtitle>Manage Shyness, Improve Your Conversations, and Make Friends, Without Giving Up Who You Are</subtitle>
        <author>Chris MacLeod</author>
        <publishingyear>2016</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com?id=SKNajwEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Social Skills Guidebook (Chris MacLeod).md</notes>
        <comments>Probably the kind of book I should have read twenty years ago. I'm shy. I've always seen it as a handicap. This book contains good "tips", but I guess they can only go so far in improving one's natural tendencies (personality, genes, etc.).</comments>
        <image>The Social Skills Guidebook.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-02-05</date>
        <title>La Fête de l'insignifiance</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>2014</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_F%C3%AAte_de_l%27insignifiance</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">La Fête de l'insignifiance (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>L'un des livres les plus courts que j'aie lu ces dernières années. Le langage est plus familier que dans les premiers livres de Kundera. Ses thèmes fétiches sont présents : les relations hommes-femmes (du point de vue de l'homme), l'histoire, le communisme, l'humour, etc. Je vais faire une comparaison incongrue, mais ce roman m'a rappelé <i>Lapinot</i> de Trondheim, où l'histoire est secondaire et où ce sont bien les discussions entre les personnages qui sont importantes.</comments>
        <image>La Fête de l'insignifiance.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2018-01-28</date>
        <title>The Expectant Father</title>
        <subtitle>The Ultimate Guide for Dads-to-Be</subtitle>
        <author>Armin A. Brott &amp; Jennifer Ash</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=nw8WQwAACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Expectant Father (Armin A. Brott &amp; Jennifer Ash).md</notes>
        <comments>A bestseller. A bit too US-centric at times, but this was expected. I skipped some parts about insurances, college savings plans, etc. I guess the rest was pretty good for that kind of books. I'll see in April/May whether it's actually useful or not...</comments>
        <image>The Expectant Father.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-12-28</date>
        <title>Prince and the Purple Rain Era Studio Sessions: 1983 and 1984</title>
        <author>Duane Tudhal</author>
        <publishingyear>2017</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=MrE5DwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Prince and the Purple Rain Era Studio Sessions - 1983 and 1984 (Duane Tudhal).md</notes>
        <comments>I didn't think I would enjoy this book as much as I did. I consider myself a harcore Prince fan. I followed him since 1989. His death in 2016 was a traumatic event. There's not much I don't know about his work and in particular about his studio work (official and unofficial). Or so I thought. Tudhal spent more than twenty years doing research for this book (and upcoming books in the same series, I hope), interviewing musicians, engineers, etc. The structure of the book is very clever. It's basically a chronological list of studio sessions, rehearsals, concerts, and major events/releases, but interspersed with relevant bits of interviews, technical details, etc. The list approach really talks to the geek in me and the interviews from different people that were there at the time (1983-84) tell a coherent story. In summary, Prince was a really special musician. I already knew that. We won't see anybody like him again, at least for a very long time. But now I really have a sense of how much time he spent in the studio, days in a row, often all night long (a lot of sessions lasting until 5-6 AM!). That's really impressive. What's also impressive is that some engineers and musicians worked with him in those conditions, some of them answering the phone in the middle of the night and coming to the studio when Prince needed them. Prince had to record music when it was in his head. He was a really hard-working artist.</comments>
        <image>Prince and the Purple Rain Era Studio Sessions - 1983 and 1984.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-11-29</date>
        <title>Paroles</title>
        <author>Jacques Prévert</author>
        <publishingyear>1946</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paroles_(Pr%C3%A9vert)</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Paroles (Jacques Prevert).md</notes>
        <comments>Le premier recueil de poèmes que j'ai lu depuis très longtemps (depuis les études, en fait). Je n'avais jamais rien lu de Prévert et ne savais pas à quoi m'attendre. J'ai été agréablement surpris par le côté absurde de ses poèmes. Et par son côté antimilitariste et anticlérical. D'un point de vue plus terre à terre, j'ai apprécié pouvoir lire un livre de manière plus découpée. Il n'y a pas vraiment de continuité, hors des thèmes, entre chaque poème. Cela permet de lire un autre livre en parallèle, par exemple. Ce recueil me motive à lire plus de poésie.</comments>
        <image>Paroles.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-10-12</date>
        <title>What If?</title>
        <subtitle>Serious Scientific Answers to Absurd Hypothetical Questions</subtitle>
        <author>Randall Munroe</author>
        <publishingyear>2014</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/What_If%3F:_Serious_Scientific_Answers_to_Absurd_Hypothetical_Questions</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">What If (Randall Munroe).md</notes>
        <comments>Not a bad book, but I must admit that, after a while, the concept (explained in the subtitle - "serious scientific answers to absurd hypothetical questions") gets a bit repetitive. But, yes, some parts were funny and I even learnt some things (and already forgot many of them!).</comments>
        <image>What If.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-09-14</date>
        <title>Keith Jarrett's The Köln Concert</title>
        <subtitle></subtitle>
        <author>Peter Elsdon</author>
        <publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=HdO7iH2Sz6IC</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Keith Jarrett's The Koln Concert (Peter Elsdon).md</notes>
        <comments>It's difficult to judge this book fairly, because I'm not a musician and a couple of chapters are pretty technical. That being said, I'm a Keith Jarrett fan, so it was interesting to read about <i>The Köln Concert</i> in several contexts: jazz in general, the 1970s, Keith Jarrett's other solo albums (<i>Facing You</i> in particular), other pianists' solo recordings (e.g. Chick Corea's), Keith Jarrett's 1975 solo tour, etc. The more "philosophical" discussions such as what it means to improvise (vs compose), what it means for a live performance to be released as an album, etc. were also quite illuminating.</comments>
        <image>Keith Jarrett's The Köln Concert.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-08-26</date>
        <title>Homo Deus</title>
        <subtitle>A Brief History of Tomorrow</subtitle>
        <author>Yuval Noah Harari</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homo_Deus:_A_Brief_History_of_Tomorrow</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Homo Deus (Yuval Noah Harari).md</notes>
        <comments>This is a book I really liked. I heard Yuval Noah Harari on <a href="http://olivier.bruchez.name/podcasts#2017-03-27">Sam Harris' podcast in March 2017</a>. And then I kept hearing about people reading <i>Sapiens</i> or <i>Homo Deus</i>, so I <em>knew</em> I had to read one of his books... I had completely forgotten about it, but Harari is a vegan, an atheist, and meditates a lot, so I can easily relate to a lot of what he has to say. He also starts his book by mentioning Ray Kurzweil, Aubrey de Grey, and Steven Pinker, people I'm very familiar with, so I was hooked from the very beginning. Now I don't agree with everything he says. This is something I had already noticed during his discussion with Sam Harris, but he uses some words very loosely. For example, he seems to use the word "religion" for "philosophy" and "ideology". I understand why he's doing it, but it doesn't make his point clearer, in my opinion. Just for reference, the word "science" (and related) appears 317 times in the book, "religion" appears 211 times, and "philosophy" appears only 27 times. He also seems to support the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-overlapping_magisteria">non-overlapping magisteria (NOMA)</a> view. I clearly don't agree with him on these points. Contrary to Kurzweil, he knows a lot about history and psychology, so he has quite a different point of view about our future. Whereas Kurzweil is very enthusiastic about uploading our minds to machines and living in virtual worlds, Harari is encouraging us to think about the relationship between intelligence and consciousness, the source of our values (in a world without gods and afterlife), and about how society and politics will work in such a future. Also for reference: <a href="https://danielmiessler.com/projects/reading/summary-homo-deus/">Daniel Miessler's summary of the book</a>.</comments>
        <image>Homo Deus.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-07-31</date>
        <title>A Guide to the Good Life</title>
        <subtitle>The Ancient Art of Stoic Joy</subtitle>
        <author>William B. Irvine</author>
        <publishingyear>2008</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=yQ59JV_9AfIC</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">A Guide to the Good Life (William B. Irvine).md</notes>
        <comments>This very book convinced me that: 1) I really need a philosophy of life 2) stoicism is a good option 3) I'm already doing a lot of things correctly (according to stoicism). These next few months, I hope to "implement" stoicism in a bit more practical and conscious way (using reminders, etc.).</comments>
        <image>A Guide to the Good Life.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-07-04</date>
        <title>Micromégas</title>
        <author>Voltaire</author>
        <publishingyear>1752</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microm%C3%A9gas</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Micromegas (Voltaire).md</notes>
        <comments>Je liste <i>Migromégas</i> ici comme livre. Il s'agit plutôt d'un conte. Un conte philosophique, selon Wikipedia. Est-ce également de la science-fiction ? On y parle de science, de visiteurs de Sirus et de Saturne. Donc je dirais que oui, mais l'idée première est bel et bien de "remettre l'être humain à sa place". Il n'est pas le centre de l'univers. L'humour est également présent dans ce conte et il est difficile de ne pas penser en tout cas un peu aux géants de Rabelais.</comments>
        <image>Micromégas.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-06-28</date>
        <title>La Plaisanterie</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1967</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Plaisanterie</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">La Plaisanterie (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <comments>Il n'y a pas grand-chose que je puisse dire à propos de ce roman qui n'ait pas été déjà dit mille fois. J'aime beaucoup Kundera. <i>La Plaisanterie</i> est son premier roman, que je n'avais pas encore lu. Il s'agissait ici de la traduction française revue par Kundera lui-même. J'ai beaucoup aimé le récit à la première personne, les personnages devenant tour à tour narrateur et leur histoire se rejoignant à la fin. Amour, politique, communisme, tradition, modernisme, vengeance, jeunesse, maturité, musique, etc. Les thèmes sont multiples et il est difficile de ne pas se laisser entraîner par les personnages de ce roman.</comments>
        <image>La Plaisanterie.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-05-21</date>
        <title>The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy</title>
        <author>Douglas Adams</author>
        <publishingyear>1979</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hitchhiker%27s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy_(novel)</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy (Douglas Adams).md</notes>
        <comments>Another classic. But of course very different from <i>Nineteen Eighty-Four</i>, which I read two months ago. This is the first book by Douglas Adams that I read. His style is surprising, in a good way. This is definitely not "serious" science fiction, which I feared would lessen my interest, but it didn't.</comments>
        <image>The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-04-30</date>
        <title>Meaning in Life and Why It Matters</title>
        <author>Susan Wolf</author>
        <publishingyear>2010</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=_eoPB9zLXFoC</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Meaning in Life and Why It Matters (Susan Wolf).md</notes>
        <comments>I'm not sure I'm convinced by Wolf's argument: "In arguing that meaningfulness is a distinctive dimension of a good life, different from both happiness and moral goodness, and that the concept of meaningfulness is essentially tied to a commitment to objective distinctions in value, I have tried to show the importance of keeping the vocabulary of meaningfulness and value alive, and of not assimilating or reducing these terms to others that we are more comfortable with in both philosophy and popular culture." I will be very (too) brief, but, intuitively, I would say that Wolf's concept of meaningfulness looks like a kind of mix between self-interest and morality, not a distinct dimension. Of course, it's still important to have a concept of a "meaningful life" and Wolf at least tries to give a definition of what "meaningfulness" is in that context, but I'm not sure this book helped me clarify anything. On the contrary, I would say it made me a bit more confused than before.</comments>
        <image>Meaning in Life and Why It Matters.gif</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-03-31</date>
        <title>Nineteen Eighty-Four</title>
        <author>George Orwell</author>
        <publishingyear>1949</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nineteen_Eighty-Four</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Nineteen Eighty-Four (George Orwell).md</notes>
        <comments>A classic. The more the story progresses, the more it becomes captivating. The ending chapters grab you by the guts, in a kind of crescendo. Many people say that "Nineteen Eighty-Four" is very relevant today, because, according to them, we're living in a society of surveillance (think Facebook, the NSA, surveillance cameras, etc.), but, for me, what strikes me the most is the similarity between the constant lies of the Party and the constant lies of people such as Donald Trump. Of course, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fake_news">fake news</a> is not a new phenomenon, but it is starting to look more and more like it is described in "Nineteen Eighty-Four".</comments>
        <image>Nineteen Eighty-Four.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-02-08</date>
        <title>Life in Light of Death</title>
        <author>James A. Lindsay</author>
        <publishingyear>2016</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=lYAPkAEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Life in Light of Death (James A. Lindsay).md</notes>
        <comments>I agree with the main message of this book. Life is short. We will die. Really die. No heaven, no persistence of a soul, no resurrection, no reincarnation (the author is an atheist). Even if we manage to live longer and/or to upload our minds to machines, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Future_of_Earth#Solar_evolution">Earth will be destroyed by the Sun at some point in the future</a>. And even if we manage to move to another planetary system and/or galaxy, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultimate_fate_of_the_universe">the universe will most probably die as well</a>. Our time is limited. We have to make the most out of it. Mainly by being kind, being with our loved ones, etc. The message is simple. Almost cheesy. This is not a "how-to" book. This is merely a warning. A reminder. I'm not sure I really learned anything. Also, the part of the book about ethical vegetarianism was pretty bad/baffling: the author seems to completely underestimate the suffering of animals in factory farms and doesn't address the environmental impact of meat.</comments>
        <image>Life in Light of Death.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-01-20</date>
        <title>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck</title>
        <subtitle>A Counterintuitive Approach to Living a Good Life</subtitle>
        <author>Mark Manson</author>
        <publishingyear>2016</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=yng_CwAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Subtle Art of Not Giving a Fuck (Mark Manson).md</notes>
        <comments>A welcome reminder that we should care less about many things. And care more about what we value the most. This is not a revolutionary way of looking at things, but a refreshing, less serious perspective on what meditation already taught me. Daniel Miessler has <a href="https://danielmiessler.com/projects/reading/summary-subtle-art-not-giving-fk/">a summary of the book on his site</a>.</comments>
        <image>The Subtle Art of Not Giving a Fuck.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2017-01-01</date>
        <title>Disparaître de soi</title>
        <subtitle>Une tentation contemporaine</subtitle>
        <author>David Le Breton</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=QVhFBgAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Disparaitre de soi (David Le Breton).md</notes>
        <comments>Un sujet intriguant (disparition volontaire ou involontaire de son identité, de ses responsabilités, etc.). Un livre malheureusement un peu répétitif. Je m'attendais aussi à une analyse plus éclairante du rôle de la technologie dans nos sociétés.</comments>
        <image>Disparaître de soi.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-12-09</date>
        <title>Childhood's End</title>
        <author>Arthur C. Clarke</author>
        <publishingyear>1953</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Childhood's_End</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Childhood's End (Arthur C. Clarke).md</notes>
        <image>Childhood's End.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-11-17</date>
        <title>Les Catilinaires</title>
        <author>Amélie Nothomb</author>
        <publishingyear>1995</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Catilinaires</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Les Catilinaires (Amelie Nothomb).md</notes>
        <image>Les Catilinaires.jpg</image>
    </book>
     <book>
        <date>2016-11-12</date>
        <title>L'emploi est mort, vive le travail !</title>
        <author>Bernard Stiegler</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=izV9CAAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">L'emploi est mort, vive le travail (Bernard Stiegler).md</notes>
        <image>L'emploi est mort, vive le travail.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-11-08</date>
        <title>Everybody Is Wrong About God</title>
        <author>James A. Lindsay</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Everybody_Is_Wrong_about_God.html?id=rLozrgEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Everybody Is Wrong About God (James A. Lindsay).md</notes>
        <image>Everybody Is Wrong About God.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-10-13</date>
        <title>L'Enfant du placard</title>
        <author>Tiffany Jaquet</author>
        <publishingyear>2016</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>http://www.plaisirdelire.ch/jaquet-tiffany/t-jaquet-lenfant-du-placard</url>
        <image>L'Enfant du placard.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-10-02</date>
        <title>Non-militarisation: countries without armies</title>
        <subtitle>Identification criteria and first findings</subtitle>
        <author>Christophe Barbey</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>http://www.peace.ax/images/stories/pdf/Christophe_Barbey_non-militarisation.pdf</url>
        <comments>More of a working paper than a book, but received as a printed book, so I'm including it here.</comments>
        <image>Non-militarisation - countries without armies.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-09-28</date>
        <title>Islam and the Future of Tolerance</title>
        <subtitle>A Dialogue</subtitle>
        <author>Sam Harris &amp; Maajid Nawaz</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Islam_and_the_Future_of_Tolerance</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Islam and the Future of Tolerance (Sam Harris &amp; Maajid Nawaz).md</notes>
        <image>Islam and the Future of Tolerance.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-09-15</date>
        <title>Plaidoyer pour les animaux</title>
        <subtitle>Vers une bienveillance pour tous</subtitle>
        <author>Matthieu Ricard</author>
        <publishingyear>2014</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=pHmuBAAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Plaidoyer pour les animaux (Matthieu Ricard).md</notes>
        <image>Plaidoyer pour les animaux.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-06-19</date>
        <title>Faith Versus Fact</title>
        <subtitle>Why Science and Religion are Incompatible</subtitle>
        <author>Jerry Coyne</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Faith_Versus_Fact.html?id=ra26oQEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Faith Versus Fact (Jerry A. Coyne).md</notes>
        <image>Faith Versus Fact.png</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-04-24</date>
        <title>L'Insoutenable Légèreté de l'être</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1984</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Insoutenable_L%C3%A9g%C3%A8ret%C3%A9_de_l%27%C3%AAtre</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">L'Insoutenable Legerete de l'etre (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <image>L'Insoutenable Légèreté de l'être.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-03-01</date>
        <title>Le Petit Prince</title>
        <author>Antoine de Saint-Exupéry</author>
        <publishingyear>1943</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Petit_Prince</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Le Petit Prince (Antoine de Saint-Exupery).md</notes>
        <image>Le Petit Prince.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2016-02-23</date>
        <title>Our Accelerating Future</title>
        <subtitle>How Superintelligence, Nanotechnology, and Transhumanism Will Transform the Planet</subtitle>
        <author>Michael M. Anissimov</author>
        <publishingyear>2015</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=iB6ICgAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Our Accelerating Future (Michael M. Anissimov).md</notes>
        <image>Our Accelerating Future.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-12-29</date>
        <title>Les Testaments trahis</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1993</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Testaments_trahis</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Les Testaments Trahis (Milan Kundera).md</notes>
        <image>Les Testaments trahis.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-12-18</date>
        <title>Functional Programming in Scala</title>
        <author>Paul Chiusano &amp; Runar Bjarnason</author>
        <publishingyear>2014</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?vid=1617290653</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Functional Programming in Scala (Paul Chiusano &amp; Runar Bjarnason).md</notes>
        <image>Functional Programming in Scala.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-10-03</date>
        <title>Hygiène de l'assassin</title>
        <author>Amélie Nothomb</author>
        <publishingyear>1992</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hygi%C3%A8ne_de_l%27assassin</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Hygiene de l'assassin (Amelie Nothomb).md</notes>
        <image>Hygiène de l'assassin.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-09-26</date>
        <title>Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman!</title>
        <author>Ralph Leighton &amp; Richard Feynman</author>
        <publishingyear>1988</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Surely_You%27re_Joking,_Mr._Feynman!</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman! (Ralph Leighton &amp; Richard Feynman).md</notes>
        <image>Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman!.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-07-19</date>
        <title>When the Tripods Came</title>
        <author>John Christopher</author>
        <publishingyear>1988</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/?title=The_Tripods#When_the_Tripods_Came</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">When the Tripods Came (John Christopher).md</notes>
        <image>When the Tripods Came.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-06-28</date>
        <title>The Pool of Fire</title>
        <author>John Christopher</author>
        <publishingyear>1968</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/?title=The_Tripods#The_Pool_of_Fire_.281968.29</url>
        <image>The Pool of Fire.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-06-20</date>
        <title>The City of Gold and Lead</title>
        <author>John Christopher</author>
        <publishingyear>1968</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tripods#The_City_of_Gold_and_Lead_.281968.29</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The City of Gold and Lead (John Christopher).md</notes>
        <image>The City of Gold and Lead.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-06-04</date>
        <title>The White Mountains</title>
        <author>John Christopher</author>
        <publishingyear>1967</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tripods#The_White_Mountains_.281967.29</url>
        <image>The White Mountains.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-05-27</date>
        <title>Bad Pharma</title>
        <author>Ben Goldacre</author>
        <publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_Pharma</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Bad Pharma (Ben Goldacre).md</notes>
        <image>Bad Pharma.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-03-24</date>
        <title>Stupeur et Tremblements</title>
        <author>Amélie Nothomb</author>
        <publishingyear>1999</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stupeur_et_Tremblements</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Stupeur et Tremblements (Amelie Nothomb).md</notes>
        <image>Stupeur et Tremblements.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2015-03-21</date>
        <title>Gargantua</title>
        <author>François Rabelais</author>
        <publishingyear>1534</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gargantua</url>
        <comments>See comments for "Pantagruel".</comments>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Gargantua (Francois Rabelais).md</notes>
        <image>Gargantua.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-12-30</date>
        <title>L'Alchimiste</title>
        <author>Paulo Coelho</author>
        <publishingyear>1988</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Alchimiste</url>
        <comments>French translation of <i>O Alquimista" by Jean Orecchioni</i>.</comments>
        <image>L'Alchimiste.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-12-23</date>
        <title>The Fear of Insignificance</title>
        <subtitle>Searching for Meaning in the Twenty-First Century</subtitle>
        <author>Carlo Strenger</author>
        <publishingyear>2011</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/The_Fear_of_Insignificance.html?id=kYkqAQAAMAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Fear of Insignificance (Carlo Strenger).md</notes>
        <image>The Fear of Insignificance.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-10-31</date>
        <title>Cosmos</title>
        <author>Carl Sagan</author>
        <publishingyear>1980</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cosmos_(book)</url>
        <image>Cosmos.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-10-18</date>
        <title>The Collected Short Stories of Roald Dahl</title>
        <author>Roald Dahl</author>
        <publishingyear>1991</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Collected_Short_Stories_of_Roald_Dahl</url>
        <image>The Collected Short Stories of Roald Dahl.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-09-27</date>
        <title>Waking Up</title>
        <subtitle>A Guide to Spirituality Without Religion</subtitle>
        <author>Sam Harris</author>
        <publishingyear>2014</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Waking_Up.html?id=dmhNAgAAQBAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Waking Up (Sam Harris).md</notes>
        <image>Waking Up.jpg</image>
    </book>
	<book>
        <date>2014-09-02</date>
        <title>A Manual for Creating Atheists</title>
        <author>Peter Boghossian</author>
        <publishingyear>2013</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/A_Manual_for_Creating_Atheists.html?id=CBzunAEACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">A Manual for Creating Atheists (Peter Boghossian).md</notes>
        <image>A Manual for Creating Atheists.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-08-11</date>
        <title>La Peste</title>
        <author>Albert Camus</author>
        <publishingyear>1947</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Peste</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">La Peste (Albert Camus).md</notes>
        <image>La Peste.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-04-26</date>
        <title>The Brain and the Meaning of Life</title>
        <author>Paul Thagard</author>
        <publishingyear>2010</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/The_Brain_and_the_Meaning_of_Life.html?id=vS9jZWduGewC</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Brain and the Meaning of Life (Paul Thagard).md</notes>
        <image>The Brain and the Meaning of Life.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-02-27</date>
        <title>Play for Scala</title>
        <subtitle>Covers Play 2</subtitle>
        <author>Peter Hilton, Erik Bakker &amp; Francisco Canedo</author>
        <publishingyear>2013</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Play_for_Scala.html?id=cV24kgEACAAJ</url>
        <image>Play for Scala.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-02-23</date>
        <title>The Now Habit</title>
        <subtitle>A Strategic Program for Overcoming Procrastination and Enjoying Guilt-Free Play</subtitle>
        <author>Neil A. Fiore</author>
        <publishingyear>2007</publishingyear>
        <rating>3.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/The_Now_Habit.html?id=obLBn7OKcI8C</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Now Habit (Neil Fiore).md</notes>
        <image>The Now Habit.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2014-01-11</date>
        <title>Consciousness</title>
        <subtitle>Confessions of a Romantic Reductionist</subtitle>
        <author>Christof Koch</author>
        <publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Consciousness.html?id=q2xDfZ_TC-gC</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Consciousness (Christof Koch).md</notes>
        <image>Confessions of a Romantic Reductionist.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2013-12-16</date>
        <title>Scala in Depth</title>
        <author>Joshua D. Suereth</author>
        <publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Scala_in_Depth.html?id=4VCfSgAACAAJ</url>
        <image>Scala in Depth.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2013-12-06</date>
        <title>Pierres à cupules et autres pierres gravées : Verbier, Bagnes et Entremont</title>
        <author>Gilbert Bruchez, Philippe Curdy &amp; François Baillifard</author>
        <publishingyear>2009</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Pierres_%C3%A0_cupules_et_autres_pierres_gra.html?id=y2h-KQEACAAJ</url>
        <!-- Cover not found online -->
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2013-11-21</date>
        <title>Pantagruel</title>
        <author>François Rabelais</author>
        <publishingyear>1532</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pantagruel</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Pantagruel (Francois Rabelais).md</notes>
        <comments>Middle French version, so quite a difficult read. Difficult to rate.</comments>
        <image>Pantagruel.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2013-10-21</date>
        <title>Métaphysique des tubes</title>
        <author>Amélie Nothomb</author>
        <publishingyear>2000</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/M%C3%A9taphysique_des_tubes</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Metaphysique des Tubes (Amelie Nothomb).md</notes>
        <image>Métaphysique des tubes.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2013-10-17</date>
        <title>The Selfish Gene</title>
        <author>Richard Dawkins</author>
        <publishingyear>2006</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Selfish_Gene</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Selfish Gene (Richard Dawkins).md</notes>
        <comments>30th Anniversary edition.</comments>
        <image>The Selfish Gene.jpg</image>
    </book>
	<book>
        <date>2013-08-01</date>
        <title>A Universe from Nothing</title>
        <author>Lawrence M. Krauss</author>
        <publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Universe_from_Nothing</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">A Universe from Nothing (Lawrence M. Krauss).md</notes>
        <image>A Universe from Nothing.jpg</image>
    </book>
	<book>
        <date>2013-06-07</date>
        <title>Le Vieil Homme et la Mer</title>
        <author>Ernest Hemingway</author>
        <publishingyear>1952</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Vieil_Homme_et_la_Mer</url>
        <comments>French translation of "The Old Man and the Sea" by Jean Dutourd.</comments>
        <image>Le Vieil Homme et la Mer.jpg</image>
    </book>
	<book>
        <date>2013-05-08</date>
        <title>Le Mythe de Sisyphe</title>
        <author>Albert Camus</author>
        <publishingyear>1942</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Mythe_de_Sisyphe</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Le Mythe de Sisyphe (Albert Camus).md</notes>
        <image>Le Mythe de Sisyphe.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2013-03-07</date>
        <title>Le Voyage d'hiver</title>
        <author>Amélie Nothomb</author>
        <publishingyear>2009</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Voyage_d'hiver</url>
        <image>Le Voyage d'hiver.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2013-02-19</date>
        <title>What I Believe</title>
        <author>Bertrand Russell</author>
        <publishingyear>1925</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/What_I_Believe</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">What I Believe (Bertrand Russell).md</notes>
        <image>What I Believe.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2013-02-04</date>
        <title>How to Create a Mind</title>
        <subtitle>The Secret of Human Thought Revealed</subtitle>
        <author>Ray Kurzweil</author>
        <publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Create_a_Mind</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">How to Create a Mind (Ray Kurzweil).md</notes>
        <image>How to Create a Mind.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2012-12-06</date>
        <title>JavaScript: The Good Parts</title>
        <author>Douglas Crockford</author>
        <publishingyear>2008</publishingyear>
        <rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/JavaScript_The_Good_Parts.html?id=PXa2bby0oQ0C</url>
        <image>JavaScript - The Good Parts.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2012-11-28</date>
        <title>L'Étranger</title>
        <author>Albert Camus</author>
        <publishingyear>1942</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27%C3%A9tranger</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">L'Etranger (Albert Camus).md</notes>
        <image>L'Étranger.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2012-11-05</date>
        <title>The Moral Landscape</title>
        <subtitle>How Science Can Determine Human Values</subtitle>
        <author>Sam Harris</author>
        <publishingyear>2010</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Moral_Landscape</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">The Moral Landscape (Sam Harris).md</notes>
        <image>The Moral Landscape.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2012-09-19</date>
        <title>You Are Not So Smart</title>
        <subtitle>Why You Have Too Many Friends on Facebook, Why Your Memory Is Mostly Fiction, and 46 Other Ways You're Deluding Yourself</subtitle>
        <author>David McRaney</author>
        <publishingyear>2011</publishingyear>
        <rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/You_Are_Not_So_Smart.html?id=7qJfuAAACAAJ</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">You Are Not So Smart (David McRaney).md</notes>
        <image>You Are Not So Smart.jpg</image>
    </book>
	<book>
		<date>2012-04-26</date>
		<title>Free Will</title>
		<author>Sam Harris</author>
		<publishingyear>2012</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Free_Will.html?id=iRpkNcRt1IcC</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Free Will (Sam Harris).md</notes>
        <image>Free Will.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2012-04-06</date>
		<title>Bad Science</title>
		<author>Ben Goldacre</author>
		<publishingyear>2008</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Bad_Science.html?id=wICuv0ePMYoC</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">Bad Science (Ben Goldacre).md</notes>
        <image>Bad Science.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2011-11-14</date>
		<title>Anything You Want</title>
        <subtitle>40 Lessons for a New Kind of Entrepreneur</subtitle>
		<author>Derek Sivers</author>
		<publishingyear>2011</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Anything_You_Want.html?id=962NZwEACAAJ</url>
        <image>Anything You Want.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2011-10-20</date>
		<title>Lying</title>
		<author>Sam Harris &amp; Annaka Harris</author>
		<publishingyear>2011</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Lying.html?id=4nMOmwEACAAJ</url>
        <image>Lying.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2011-08-13</date>
		<title>God's Debris</title>
		<subtitle>A Thought Experiment</subtitle>
		<author>Scott Adams</author>
		<publishingyear>2001</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/God%27s_Debris</url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights">God's Debris (Scott Adams).md</notes>
        <image>God's Debris.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2011-07-08</date>
		<title>Institutions politiques suisses</title>
		<author>Vincent Golay &amp; Mix &amp; Remix</author>
		<publishingyear>2010</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Institutions_politiques_suisses.html?id=wPdyAAAACAAJ</url>
        <image>Institutions politiques suisses.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2011-03-20</date>
		<title>Programming in Scala</title>
		<author>Martin Odersky, Lex Spoon &amp; Bill Venners</author>
		<publishingyear>2008</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Programming_in_Scala.html?id=MFjNhTjeQKkC</url>
        <image>Programming in Scala.png</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2011-02-01</date>
		<title>The Immortality Edge</title>
		<subtitle>Realize the Secrets of Your Telomeres for a Longer, Healthier Life</subtitle>
		<author>Michael Fossel, Greta Blackburn &amp; Dave Woynarowski</author>
		<publishingyear>2010</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/The_Immortality_Edge.html?id=loTusEZNu7oC</url>
        <image>The Immortality Edge.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2010-09-27</date>
		<title>Stumbling on Happiness</title>
		<author>Daniel Gilbert</author>
		<publishingyear>2006</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stumbling_on_Happiness</url>
        <image>Stumbling on Happiness.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2010-08-30</date>
		<title>Trick or Treatment?</title>
		<subtitle>Alternative Medicine on Trial</subtitle>
		<author>Simon Singh &amp; Edzard Ernst</author>
		<publishingyear>2008</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trick_or_Treatment</url>
        <image>Alternative Medicine on Trial.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2010-07-01</date>
		<title>Placebo</title>
		<subtitle>Mind over Matter in Modern Medicine</subtitle>
		<author>Dylan Evans</author>
		<publishingyear>2004</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Placebo.html?id=GDUuMHQO6nMC</url>
        <image>Placebo.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2010-06-03</date>
		<title>L'effet placebo</title>
		<subtitle>Le pouvoir de guérir</subtitle>
		<author>Danielle Fecteau</author>
		<publishingyear>2005</publishingyear>
		<rating>2.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/L_effet_placebo.html?id=v3unAAAACAAJ</url>
        <image>L'effet placebo.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2010-04-30</date>
		<title>Tribal Leadership</title>
		<subtitle>Leveraging Natural Groups to Build a Thriving Organization</subtitle>
		<author>Dave Logan, John King &amp; Halee Fischer-Wright</author>
		<publishingyear>2008</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tribal_Leadership</url>
        <image>Tribal Leadership.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2010-02-16</date>
		<title>La Petite Marchande de prose</title>
		<author>Daniel Pennac</author>
		<publishingyear>1990</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Petite_Marchande_de_prose</url>
        <image>La Petite Marchande de prose.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2009-08-16</date>
		<title>La fée carabine</title>
		<author>Daniel Pennac</author>
		<publishingyear>1987</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_F%C3%A9e_Carabine</url>
        <image>La fée carabine.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2009-06-27</date>
		<title>Transcend</title>
		<subtitle>Nine Steps to Living Well Forever</subtitle>
		<author>Ray Kurzweil &amp; Terry Grossman</author>
		<publishingyear>2009</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Transcend.html?id=J0XFdYjYE9AC</url>
        <image>Transcend.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2009-06-12</date>
		<title>Au bonheur des ogres</title>
		<author>Daniel Pennac</author>
		<publishingyear>1985</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Au_bonheur_des_ogres</url>
        <image>Au bonheur des ogres.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2009-05-27</date>
		<title>Je suis fatigué mais je ne sais pas pourquoi...!</title>
		<subtitle>La fatigue chronique, fléau des temps modernes</subtitle>
		<author>Philippe-Gaston Besson</author>
		<publishingyear>2000</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Je_suis_fatigu%C3%A9_mais_je_ne_sais_pas_pou.html?id=Br4TAAAACAAJ</url>
        <image>Je suis fatigué mais je ne sais pas pourquoi.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2009-05-27</date>
		<title>Le garçon qui croyait au paradis</title>
		<author>Maurice Chappaz</author>
		<publishingyear>1995</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Le_gar%C3%A7on_qui_croyait_au_paradis.html?id=-5kbAQAAIAAJ</url>
        <image>Le garçon qui croyait au paradis.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2009-05-18</date>
		<title>Fantastic Voyage</title>
		<subtitle>Live Long Enough To Live Forever</subtitle>
		<author>Ray Kurzweil &amp; Terry Grossman</author>
		<publishingyear>2004</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantastic_Voyage:_Live_Long_Enough_to_Live_Forever</url>
        <image>Fantastic Voyage.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2009-04-25</date>
		<title>Chagrin d'école</title>
		<author>Daniel Pennac</author>
		<publishingyear>2007</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chagrin_d%27%C3%A9cole</url>
        <image>Chagrin d'école.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2009-04-10</date>
		<title>Asiles de fous</title>
		<author>Régis Jauffret</author>
		<publishingyear>2005</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asiles_de_fous</url>
        <image></image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2009-03-27</date>
		<title>Ulysse from Bagdad</title>
		<author>Eric-Emmanuel Schmitt</author>
		<publishingyear>2008</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ulysse_from_Bagdad</url>
        <image>Ulysse from Bagdad.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2009-03-08</date>
		<title>L'Automne à Pékin</title>
		<author>Boris Vian</author>
		<publishingyear>1947</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Automne_%C3%A0_P%C3%A9kin</url>
        <image>L'Automne à Pékin.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2008-12-29</date>
		<title>Professional Web 2.0 Programming</title>
		<author>Eric van der Vlist, Danny Ayers, Erik Bruchez, Joe Fawcett &amp; Alessandro Vernet</author>
		<publishingyear>2006</publishingyear>
		<rating>3.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Professional_Web_2_0_Programming.html?id=hyV-IX8W30QC</url>
        <image>Professional Web 2.0 Programming.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
		<date>2008-12-17</date>
		<title>365 jours pour réfléchir à notre Terre</title>
		<author>Yann Arthus-Bertrand</author>
		<publishingyear>2006</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/365_jours_pour_r%C3%A9fl%C3%A9chir_%C3%A0_notre_Terr.html?id=5P7GAwAACAAJ</url>
        <image>365 jours pour réfléchir à notre Terre.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2008-08-17</date>
		<title>Thinking In Java</title>
		<author>Bruce Eckel</author>
		<publishingyear>2006</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thinking_in_Java</url>
        <image>Thinking In Java.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2008-03-24</date>
		<title>JPod</title>
		<author>Douglas Coupland</author>
		<publishingyear>2006</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JPod</url>
        <image>JPod.gif</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2008-02-16</date>
		<title>The 4-Hour Workweek</title>
		<subtitle>Escape 9-5, Live Anywhere, And Join The New Rich</subtitle>
		<author>Timothy Ferriss</author>
		<publishingyear>2007</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.75</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_4-Hour_Workweek</url>
        <image>The 4-Hour Workweek.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2008-01-28</date>
		<title>Getting Things Done</title>
		<subtitle>The Art Of Stress-Free Productivity</subtitle>
		<author>David Allen</author>
		<publishingyear>2002</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done</url>
        <image>Getting Things Done.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2007-07-08</date>
		<title>L'Élégance du hérisson</title>
		<author>Muriel Barbery</author>
		<publishingyear>2006</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27%C3%89l%C3%A9gance_du_h%C3%A9risson</url>
        <image>L'Élégance du hérisson.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2007-05-08</date>
		<title>Petit traité de manipulation à l'usage des honnêtes gens</title>
		<author>Robert-Vincent Joule &amp; Jean-Léon Beauvois</author>
		<publishingyear>2002</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.25</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Petit_trait%C3%A9_de_manipulation_%C3%A0_l%27usage_des_honn%C3%AAtes_gens</url>
        <notes description="Handwritten notes">Petit traite de manipulation a l'usage des honnetes gens (Robert-Vincent Joule &amp; Jean-Leon Beauvois).pdf</notes>
        <image>Petit traité de manipulation à l'usage des honnêtes gens.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2007-02-25</date>
		<title>The God Delusion</title>
		<author>Richard Dawkins</author>
		<publishingyear>2006</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_God_Delusion</url>
        <image>The God Delusion.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2006-10-10</date>
		<title>L'Écume des jours</title>
		<author>Boris Vian</author>
		<publishingyear>1947</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27%C3%89cume_des_jours</url>
        <image>L'Écume des jours.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2006-08-20</date>
		<title>The Singularity Is Near</title>
		<subtitle>When Humans Transcend Biology</subtitle>
		<author>Ray Kurzweil</author>
		<publishingyear>2005</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Singularity_Is_Near</url>
        <image>The Singularity Is Near.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2006-05-14</date>
		<title>The Da Vinci Code</title>
		<author>Dan Brown</author>
		<publishingyear>2003</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Da_Vinci_Code</url>
        <image>The Da Vinci Code.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2005-08-16</date>
		<title>Le Soleil des Scorta</title>
		<author>Laurent Gaudé</author>
		<publishingyear>2004</publishingyear>
		<rating>4.5</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Soleil_des_Scorta</url>
        <image>Le Soleil des Scorta.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2005-06-10</date>
		<title>L'Ignorance</title>
		<author>Milan Kundera</author>
		<publishingyear>2003</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.0</rating>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Ignorance</url>
        <image>L'Ignorance.jpg</image>
	</book>
	<book>
		<date>2005-05-22</date>
		<title>The Last Miles</title>
		<subtitle>The Music of Miles Davis 1980-1991</subtitle>
		<author>George Cole</author>
		<publishingyear>2005</publishingyear>
		<rating>5.25</rating>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/The_Last_Miles.html?id=ZcnGp0740TMC</url>
        <image>The Last Miles.jpg</image>
	</book>
    <book>
        <date>2004-09-19</date>
        <title>The Age of Spiritual Machines</title>
        <author>Ray Kurzweil</author>
        <publishingyear>1999</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Age_of_Spiritual_Machines</url>
        <image>The Age of Spiritual Machines.jpg</image>
    </book>
	<book>
        <date>2004-02-10</date>
        <title>Miroirs et fumée</title>
        <author>Neil Gaima</author>
        <publishingyear>1998</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miroirs_et_fum%C3%A9e</url>
        <image>Miroirs et fumée.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2004-01-24</date>
        <title>Le Procès</title>
        <author>Franz Kafka</author>
        <publishingyear>1933</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Proc%C3%A8s</url>
        <image>Le Procè̀s.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2002-??-??</date>
        <title>Les Testaments trahis</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1993</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Testaments_trahis</url>
        <image>Les Testaments trahis.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2002-05-04</date>
        <title>Miles Beyond</title>
        <subtitle>The Electric Explorations of Miles Davis 1967-1991</subtitle>
        <author>Paul Tingen</author>
        <publishingyear>2001</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Miles_Beyond.html?id=LA_2EZtLQ5AC</url>
        <image>Miles Beyond.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2001-09-26</date>
        <title>Le Château</title>
        <author>Franz Kafka</author>
        <publishingyear>1938</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Le_Ch%C3%A2teau</url>
        <image>Le Château.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2000-??-??</date>
        <title>La vie est ailleurs</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1969</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_vie_est_ailleurs</url>
        <image>La vie est ailleurs.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>2000-02-??</date>
        <title>Le mystère de la conscience</title>
        <author>John Searle</author>
        <publishingyear>1999</publishingyear>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books?id=ff41AAAACAAJ</url>
        <image>Le mystère de la conscience.jpg</image>
    </book> 
    <book>
        <date>1999-??-??</date>
        <title>Keith Jarrett</title>
        <subtitle>The Man And His Music</subtitle>
        <author>Ian Carr</author>
        <publishingyear>1991</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Keith_Jarrett.html?id=HhWLjNdg3uUC</url>
        <image>Keith Jarrett - The Man And His Music.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>1998-??-??</date>
        <title>Miles</title>
        <subtitle>L'autobiographie</subtitle>
        <author>Miles Davis &amp; Quincy Troupe</author>
        <publishingyear>1991</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://books.google.com/books/about/Miles.html?id=puBfGwAACAAJ</url>
        <image>Miles - L'autobiographie.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>1996-??-??</date>
        <title>L'Amérique</title>
        <author>Franz Kafka</author>
        <publishingyear>1927</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Am%C3%A9rique</url>
        <comments>Read in 1995 or 1996.</comments>
        <image>L'Amérique.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>1996-09-21</date>
        <title>La Modification</title>
        <author>Michel Butor</author>
        <publishingyear>1957</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Modification</url>
        <image>La Modification.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>1996-07-08</date>
        <title>Plume</title>
        <author>Henri Michaux</author>
        <publishingyear>1938</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plume_(Michaux)</url>
        <image>Plume.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>1996-07-04</date>
        <title>Comme un roman</title>
        <author>Daniel Pennac</author>
        <publishingyear>1992</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comme_un_roman</url>
        <image>Comme un roman.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>1996-07-01</date>
        <title>L'insoutenable légèreté de l'être</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1984</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%27Insoutenable_L%C3%A9g%C3%A8ret%C3%A9_de_l%27%C3%AAtre</url>
        <image>L'Insoutenable Légèreté de l'être.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>199?-??-??</date>
        <title>2010 : Odyssée deux</title>
        <author>Arthur C. Clarke</author>
        <publishingyear>1982</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/2010_:_Odyss%C3%A9e_deux</url>
        <image>2010 - Odyssée deux.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>199?-??-??</date>
        <title>2001 : L'Odyssée de l'espace</title>
        <author>Arthur C. Clarke</author>
        <publishingyear>1968</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/2001_:_l%27Odyss%C3%A9e_de_l%27espace_(roman)</url>
        <image>2001 - L'Odyssée de l'espace.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book>
        <date>199?-??-??</date>
        <title>La Lenteur</title>
        <author>Milan Kundera</author>
        <publishingyear>1994</publishingyear>
        <rating/>
        <url>https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Lenteur</url>
        <image>La Lenteur.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <!--
    <book>
        <date></date>
        <title></title>
        <subtitle></subtitle>
        <author></author>
        <publishingyear></publishingyear>
        <rating></rating>
        <url></url>
        <notes description="Kindle highlights"></notes>
        <comments></comments>
        <image></image>
    </book>
    -->
	<!--
	Kundera, Kafka, Sartre, etc. + livre lu dans les années '90 parlant de l'ABS, etc.
	-->
</books>
